FULL-STACK UX DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

Over ten years ago, I graduated with a degree in Graphic Design, but soon realized the world of design held a lot more than infographics and banner ads.

My current role as a Senior UX Designer/Consultant includes working on complex design systems, taking part in Design Thinking workshops to inform prototypes and help clients unlock ideas, and helping mentor younger designers.

I live in Seattle and enjoy hiking with my wife and pets, video games, books, and movies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SLALOM: SENIOR UX DESIGNER/CONSULTANT: APRIL 2019 - PRESENT

- · Lead projects in user-centered design solutions using Design Thinking methodologies
- Work with development teams and project leadership to define and refine scope
- Produce wireframes, user flows, IA diagrams and prototypes for web and mobile experiences, manage design assets, and review UI for proper implementation

PUSH INTERACTIVE: LEAD UX/UI DESIGNER: DECEMBER 2017 - APRIL 2019

- Researched and managed projects, providing leadership and direction
- · Began research and initial development of new design system
- Collaborated with cross-functional team to create solutions that stressed empathy to the user, strived for accessibility, and maintained attention to detail

THINKSEM: CREATIVE DIRECTOR: MAY 2011 - NOVEMBER 2017

- Curated current and new design services and continually improved capabilities
- Lead a design team concentrating on web standards and user experience by utilizing analytics, content strategy, and accessibility
- Used client/team feedback in combination with critical thinking to create the most optimized web experiences possible
- Created a client focused web theme site that introduced highly valuable capabilities and a new source of revenue for the agency

THE LACEK GROUP: FRONT-END DEVELOPER: DECEMBER 2010 - MAY 2011

- Created microsites, single page sites, and HTML emails for clients such as American Airlines and Enterprise Rent-A-Car with a cohesive interactive design team
- Worked extensively with testing software (Litmus) to provide support for a multitude of email clients

GLOBE UNIVERSITY: WEB DESIGNER: NOVEMBER 2009 - DECEMBER 2010

- Designed, developed, and maintained university websites in collaboration with design and IT teams
- Created wireframes and mock-ups to communicate with internal stakeholders ensuring visual designs met brand and usability standards
- Worked in .NET environment to bring front-end designs into Sitefinity CMS

LANCER HOSPITALITY: GRAPHIC DESIGNER: MAY 2008 - NOVEMBER 2009

- Collaborated with the art director in a fast-paced environment to create print designs including pamphlets, posters, and menus
- Showed decisiveness and the ability to be a self-starter by pitching, creating, and maintaining connected web experiences for online properties that included a restaurant, child care dining, and ongoing events

BOOZ ALLEN HAMILTON: GRAPHIC DESIGNER (PAID INTERNSHIP): JUNE 2007 - DECEMBER 2007

• Worked with internal stakeholders to provide print and digital design deliverables

WISCONSIN ARMY NATIONAL GUARD: SERGEANT: AUGUST 1998 - AUGUST 2008

- Ultimately worked in a leadership role (88M, 92A) as part of several units
- Served year-long tour in Operation Iraqi Freedom in support role transporting equipment and personnel from various locations in Iraq back to base in Kuwait

SKILL SET

- Project/Client Consultation
- · Design Thinking
- · Usability Testing
- User Experience Design
- Information Architecture
- Responsive Website Design
- Front-end (HTML/CSS/JS)
- Strive for Accessibility
- Cross Browser Support/Device Testing
- Prototypes
- Confident
- Open to Critical Feedback

SOME TOOLS I USE

- Miro
- Balsamiq
- Figma
- Sketch
- InVision
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Sublime Text
- CodeKit
- BrowserStack
- $\bullet \, Zeplin$

EDUCATION/ACHIEVEMENTS

WINONA STATE UNIVERSITY

BA in Graphic Design w/minor in Marketing

CONTINUED EDUCATION

- Online courses
- CSS Tricks tips/tutorials
- A List Apart
- InVision Blog

MILITARY ACHIEVEMENTS

- · Commandant's Honor List
- Army Achievement Medal
- Overseas Service Ribbon